### **BRANDY CARDONA**

#### **ABOUT ME**

IT professional with over 10 years of experience in Child Support software testing, design, development, and maintenance; and almost 20 years of experience in various aspects of state government. Seeking a technical consulting position to apply in-depth knowledge of child support enforcement, ensuring successful implementation of modernization projects.

# CHILD SUPPORT PROJECTS

#### **NVKIDS, 2018 - PRESENT**

Participated in Nevada Child Support Modernization project including requirement clarification sessions, joint technical and functional design sessions, conversion mapping, review of parallel testing results, interface design and user acceptance testing, implementation, management of phased rollout activities in legacy system, and post implementation activities.

### **RAPID, 2018**

Assisted with design and implementation of State Collection and Disbursement Unit's new system, RAPID.

#### EIWO, 2017

Lead developer for design, development, and implementation of Electronic Income Withholding (eIWO) program for the State of Nevada.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## IT PROFESSIONAL, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, DIVISION OF WELFARE AND SUPPORTIVE SERVICES

October 2013 - Present

Develop, maintain, and design enhancements for mainframe and java applications used by the Child Support Enforcement Program. Review and analyze help desk tickets for issues reported by system users and participate in joint application design meetings.

# BUSINESS PROCESS ANALYST, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, DIVISION OF WELFARE AND SUPORTIVE SERVICES

October 2012 – October 2013

Develop test plans which involve attending user requirement meetings and reviewing System Requirement Documents to identify functionality and potential problems for work items. Ensure systems are functioning as designed through the testing of all user requirements and creating and retesting defects. Execute batch processes that simulate time passage in non-production environments as required for testing purposes. Manage Bugzilla software and triage defects entered by staff.

# IT TECHNICIAN, STATE OF NEVADA, DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND NATURAL RESOURCES, DIVISION OF WATER RESOURCES

October 2011 – October 2012

Manage work flows for creation and maintenance of water right data into the Division's existing datasets; maintenance of SQL data; assist staff and public with cartographic needs, querying of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) data, and post processing of field collection data; and develop training sessions for Division staff on the use of GIS software and data. Additional duties include assisting staff with technical report writing, and technical and statutory review of water right applications and application maps for publication.

#### **EDUCATION**

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF PHOENIX, 2011

Earned a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology with a concentration in Multimedia and Visual Communication. Program focuses on essential knowledge in core technologies such as systems analysis and design, database design, web technologies, and application development, implementation, and maintenance. The Multimedia and Visual Communication concentration emphasizes skills needed to facilitate internal and external communications, information content management, training, and marketing materials.

# ASSOCIATE OF APPLIED SCIENCE IN GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS, WESTERN NEVADA COLLEGE, 2004

The GIS program at WNC covered core theories and competencies of spatial analysis, GIS databases, cartography, GIS trends and applications, and ArcGIS desktop and extensions. Completed internship and portfolio while working for the State of Nevada, Division of Forestry. Portfolio was based on analysis of the spread of Pinyon Ips in Western Nevada.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Eclipse
- Visual Studio
- Rational Application Developer
- Rational Business Developer
- Perforce Helix ALM
- Perforce Helix Core
- Bugzilla
- Toad for DB2
- GIMP
- WinSCP
- Java
- Enterprise Generation Language
- SQL/DB2
- HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

Page | 2 Brandy Cardona